<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | ncatarino.github.io]]></title>
  <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-22T18:37:32+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nuno Catarino]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prometheus]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/1146"/>
    <updated>2012-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/prometheus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">
  <iframe width="620" height="415" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/HHcHYisZFLU "></iframe>
</p>




<p style="text-align: center;">
  Very, very, <em>very</em> excited about this.
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Old Movies]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/879"/>
    <updated>2011-07-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/old-movies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s something about old 60&#8242;s/70&#8242;s movies that makes me love them. I can&#8217;t really say why, they just do. I&#8217;ve been running this sort of old movie marathon and all I can think of is how most of the time I enjoy them a hell of  a lot more than recent ones.</p>

<p>I remember when I was a kid spending entire weekend afternoons watching movies on TV and for some reason those days seemed to last longer and packed with great stuff on the tube. I can&#8217;t really put this into words so I won&#8217;t keep trying.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t remember much about my childhood, people usually say this is because I had a happy childhood and I think that&#8217;s true. But sitting on my living room&#8217;s couch watching movies is a vivid clear memory I have. My parents even bought me a VHS VCR eventually and that was a big deal at the time. Those things were expensive! From then on I became a regular at the local movie rental place. I don&#8217;t remember how the ladies at the counter looked like but I do remember they were always nice to me and usually greeted me with a smile every time they saw me.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>So, here are the movies I&#8217;ve seen on this marathon. I recommend each and every one of them.</p>

<ul>
<li>Colossus. The Forbin Project. &#8211; <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0064177/" target="_blank">IMDB</a></span></li>
<li>Quintet &#8211; <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0079770/" target="_blank">IMDB</a></span></li>
<li>The Quiet Earth &#8211; <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0089869/" target="_blank">IMDB</a></span></li>
<li>The Dunwich Horror &#8211; <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0065669/" target="_blank"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">IMDB</span> </a></li>
</ul>


<div>
  I really really <em>really</em> liked The Quiet Earth, I think it made it into my top 50 movies of all time. As for The Dunwich Horror, I think it&#8217;s too bad not enough movies explore the Lovecraft setting.  <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001777/" target="_blank">Dean Stockwell</a> is also one of my favorite actors, I noticed that while watching this movie. He&#8217;s in a lot of stuff that I love and one of the vivid memories I mentioned earlier also includes watching him on Quantum Leap.
</div>


<p>&nbsp;</p>

<div>
  I also saw 500 Days of Summer (IMDB), but that one doesn&#8217;t exactly belong in that list. It&#8217;s not bad, but it&#8217;s not that great either. It tried to be something other than a romantic comedy with a happy ending but it turned out to be exactly that.
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Priest &#038; Stake Land]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/852"/>
    <updated>2011-06-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/priest-stake-land</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You know when sometimes you start watching a movie thinking it&#8217;s going to be rather cheesy and you&#8217;re generally just in it for the fun of watching things explode and monsters cut into pieces and <em>then</em> the movie is actually one of the best you&#8217;ve seen lately? Yeah.. That happened to me twice in the past week.</p>

<p>I began watching <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0822847/" target="_blank">Priest</a> with a pre-defined notion it was &#8220;vampire ass kicking movie&#8221; with <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0079273/" target="_blank">Paul Bettany</a> and I pretty much like everything he&#8217;s in. Turns out there&#8217;s <em>so</em> much more to the movie than that. The plot sounds like the cheesiest thing ever but they actually pull it off quite nicely. I was reminded of two movies while watching it, Blade Runner and Equilibrium. The cityscape is one of the most beautiful I&#8217;ve seen in a while and the action isn&#8217;t bad either. Granted it&#8217;s an action movie, lots of it going on, but this movie has lots of eye candy as well. I really recommend it.</p>

<p>The other one was <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1464580/" target="_blank">Stake Land</a>. Nothing in imbd&#8217;s page prepared me for the great movie this turned out to be. It&#8217;s no masterpiece, but it&#8217;s one of the best horror flicks I&#8217;ve seen in a <em>long</em> while. The acting is great, the scenery is awesome, the story is compelling with some twists in it that made me go &#8220;Whoa.&#8221; and I really felt sad when some of the stuff on there happened (no spoilers!). To put it simply, if you&#8217;re a horror fan you <em><strong>have</strong> </em>to see it. You know that feeling you got when you saw <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0289043/" target="_blank">28 Days Later</a> and thought to yourself that was a damn good movie? Watch this one then :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Year Uptime, Rift and Some Other Stuff]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/843"/>
    <updated>2011-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/one-year-uptime-rift-and-some-other-stuff</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>No idea what was the exact day I bought the domain/hosting and started working on this site as a hobby, but it&#8217;s been roughly a year now. I know this because I had to renew it all, sometimes I wonder if it&#8217;s worth it since I end up spending quite some time without paying any attention to it. I guess that&#8217;s the nature of such sites :)</p>

<p>Been spending a *lot* of time playing Rift, I&#8217;m quite amazed how good something I&#8217;ve never heard of till about a couple of months ago can be. Couple of guys I know mentioned the open beta was up and I tried it. A few hours after I found myself buying it. I had recently restarted playing WoW but as soon as the month&#8217;s subscription ended I was finding myself really bored with it and Rift was entering it&#8217;s head start for pre-order customers. Perfect timing. Dragon Age 2 is supposed to be coming out too, that&#8217;s another one to check out.</p>

<p>Haven&#8217;t spent much time around my Spica as of lately, which is just as well since development for the Cyanogenmod Spica beta seems to have come to a halt. Probably because everything&#8217;s working quite well and it really shouldn&#8217;t be called a beta anymore. Been using the 8.3 beta for a few months now and it&#8217;s working like a charm.</p>

<p>Also, saw Tron Legacy the other day. Awesome sauce.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Silent City]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/806"/>
    <updated>2010-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/the-silent-city</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/silent.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-807" title="Silent City" src="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/silent.jpg" alt="" width="520" height="296" /></a></p>

<p>The Silent City: an awesome short film by Ruairi Robinson featuring 3 soldiers, Cillian Murphy, Don Wycherly, and Garvan McGrath, trying to survive on a desolate planet. After hitting play, make sure the player is in HD mode, and then, watch it in full screen. Enjoy!</p>

<p style="text-align: center;">
</p>




<p style="text-align: left;">
  [<a href="http://www.geeksaresexy.net/2010/11/18/featured-short-film-the-silent-city-hd/" target="_blank">Via</a>]
</p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
