<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Rubik | ncatarino.github.io]]></title>
  <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/blog/categories/rubik/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-22T18:35:46+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nuno Catarino]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Recent Cube4you Order]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/1072"/>
    <updated>2011-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/cube4you-and-ups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I finally ordered some cubes from Cube4you. I have to say that the shipping prices are a real pita but somewhat understandable since it comes all the way from Shanghai, China. Cube4you was awesomely fast sending the stuff, I made the order on a saturday and it was ready for UPS pick up the very next day even it being a sunday. Let&#8217;s hope they didn&#8217;t get any of the orders wrong now :p</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s a list of what I ordered, one of each.</p>

<ul>
<li>Dayan Guhong 3x3x3 DIYKit &#8211; Black</li>
<li>Cube4you 3x3x3 DYI Speed Cube &#8211; Black</li>
<li>New Type-A 3x3x3 DIYKit &#8211; White</li>
<li>Type F-II 3x3x3 Cube (NIB) &#8211; White</li>
<li>Diangsheng 3x3x3 &#8211; White</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<p>They should be here by wednesday and I&#8217;m quite excited about it. Kinda amazed it only takes 3 business days to come all the way from China to Portugal.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve also been chatting a bit on an online forum with other portuguese cubers about trying to find a decent lubricant over here. Seems like the best is a &#8220;3 en uno &#8211; lubrificante de silicona&#8221; I had already got at a shop called AKI and made by the same maker than WD40 but I&#8217;m not sure I like it that much. I only have 2 Rubik&#8217;s Brand cubes to speak for at the moment, so it might be the quality of the plastic that isn&#8217;t that good together with this specific lube or possibly the lack of spring/screw tension adjustment.</p>

<p>I plan to check the new cubes when they arrive and try it on the cube that I enjoy the less and see how it behaves after I spray it a bit. If I still don&#8217;t like it maybe I&#8217;ll order some Lubix online, though the price kinda scares me off a bit.</p>

<p>One of the posters mentioned some sort of silicone oil we can buy at model shops used to fuel or lube car/plane models or something. Maybe I&#8217;ll give that a try, I used to have a model shop close by but I&#8217;m not so sure it&#8217;s still there. We&#8217;ll see.</p>

<p>So yeah, my cube collection will grow quite a bit with this purchase. Oddly enough the prices weren&#8217;t what hurt my wallet the most, the shipping was. At least compared to what I already bought over time:</p>

<ul>
<li>2x Rubik&#8217;s Brand 3x3x3</li>
<li>Rubik&#8217;s Brand 3x3x3 keychain</li>
<li>Rubik&#8217;s Brand 5x5x5 (it suuuucks)</li>
<li>Eastsheen 2x2x2</li>
<li>V-Cube 5</li>
<li>V-Cube 6</li>
<li>V-Cube 7</li>
<li>Fluorescent sticker 3x3x3 with no brand &#8211; lol</li>
</ul>


<p>It&#8217;d be really nice if I can get my hands on a Eastsheen 4x4x4 and a decent Megaminx. But I guess that&#8217;ll have to wait a while since little by little all these purchases can end up making a serious dent on anyone&#8217;s wallet, even if it&#8217;s just 4-6€ a pop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
