<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tech | ncatarino.github.io]]></title>
  <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/blog/categories/tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-22T18:55:57+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nuno Catarino]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using LaTeX in Portuguese]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/1556"/>
    <updated>2013-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/using-latex-in-portuguese</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been using LaTeX for a couple of small projects recently and I had some trouble figuring out how to make the accented characters as well as stuff like &#8216;Ç&#8217; render correctly in the end product. After some mucking about I learned that we have to use three extra packages so everything shows up nicely in the end. It probably works just as well for other languages but you may want to refer to the documentation. Here are the packages you have to use:</p>

<p><code>tex Packages
\usepackage[portuguese]{babel}
\usepackage[utf8]{inputenc}
\usepackage[T1]{fontenc}
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My .bashrc]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/1552"/>
    <updated>2013-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/my-bashrc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&#8217;s something I keep forgetting to save and/or backup, my .bashrc. The last couple of times I reinstalled or switched to another distribution I <em>did</em> remember to backup my dotfiles but I figured I might as well just post it here in case I ever need it again.</p>

<p>Most of it comes from the Arch Linux Wiki, a great place for Linux information even if you <em>don&#8217;t</em> use Arch. I have then made a few tweaks from snippets I found on other websites. I can&#8217;t remember all of them since at the time I had no intention of posting this here. If you find anything that you think is yours please send me the article link so I can pingback to it. Keep in mind there are some Arch specific sections in there, feel free to edit and redistribute as you see fit.</p>

<p>Since it&#8217;s quite a wall of text, I&#8217;ll drop it after a break for the website proper. If you&#8217;re reading this through an RSS reader, sorry for the wall of text.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>``` bash .bashrc</p>

<h1>/etc/bash.bashrc</h1>

<p>#</p>

<h1>This file is sourced by all <em>interactive</em> bash shells on startup,</h1>

<h1>including some apparently interactive shells such as scp and rcp</h1>

<h1>that can&rsquo;t tolerate any output. So make sure this doesn&rsquo;t display</h1>

<h1>anything or bad things will happen !</h1>

<h1>Test for an interactive shell. There is no need to set anything</h1>

<h1>past this point for scp and rcp, and it&rsquo;s important to refrain from</h1>

<h1>outputting anything in those cases.</h1>

<h1>If not running interactively, don&rsquo;t do anything!</h1>

<p>[[ $&ndash; != <em>i</em> ]] &amp;&amp; return</p>

<h1>Bash won&rsquo;t get SIGWINCH if another process is in the foreground.</h1>

<h1>Enable checkwinsize so that bash will check the terminal size when</h1>

<h1>it regains control.</h1>

<h1><a href="http://cnswww.cns.cwru.edu/~chet/bash/FAQ">http://cnswww.cns.cwru.edu/~chet/bash/FAQ</a> (E11)</h1>

<p>shopt -s checkwinsize</p>

<h1>Enable history appending instead of overwriting.</h1>

<p>shopt -s histappend</p>

<p>case ${TERM} in</p>

<pre><code>xterm*|rxvt*|Eterm|aterm|kterm|gnome*)
    PROMPT_COMMAND=${PROMPT_COMMAND:+$PROMPT_COMMAND; }'printf "\033]0;%s@%s:%s\007" "${USER}" "${HOSTNAME%%.*}" "${PWD/#$HOME/~}"'
    ;;
screen)
    PROMPT_COMMAND=${PROMPT_COMMAND:+$PROMPT_COMMAND; }'printf "\033_%s@%s:%s\033\\" "${USER}" "${HOSTNAME%%.*}" "${PWD/#$HOME/~}"'
    ;;
</code></pre>

<p>esac</p>

<h1>Set colorful PS1 only on colorful terminals.</h1>

<h1>dircolors &mdash;print-database uses its own built-in database</h1>

<h1>instead of using /etc/DIR_COLORS. Try to use the external file</h1>

<h1>first to take advantage of user additions. Use internal bash</h1>

<h1>globbing instead of external grep binary.</h1>

<h1>sanitize TERM:</h1>

<p>safe_term=${TERM//[^[:alnum:]]/?}
match_lhs=&ldquo;&rdquo;</p>

<p>[[ -f ~/.dir_colors ]] &amp;&amp; match_lhs=&ldquo;${match_lhs}$(&lt;~/.dir_colors)&rdquo;
[[ -f /etc/DIR_COLORS ]] &amp;&amp; match_lhs=&ldquo;${match_lhs}$(&lt;/etc/DIR_COLORS)&rdquo;
[[ -z ${match_lhs} ]] \</p>

<pre><code>&amp;&amp; type -P dircolors &gt;/dev/null \
&amp;&amp; match_lhs=$(dircolors --print-database)
</code></pre>

<p>if [[ $&lsquo;\n&rsquo;${match_lhs} == <em>$&lsquo;\n&rsquo;&ldquo;TERM &rdquo;${safe_term}</em> ]] ; then</p>

<pre><code># we have colors :-)

# Enable colors for ls, etc. Prefer ~/.dir_colors
if type -P dircolors &gt;/dev/null ; then
    if [[ -f ~/.dir_colors ]] ; then
        eval $(dircolors -b ~/.dir_colors)
    elif [[ -f /etc/DIR_COLORS ]] ; then
        eval $(dircolors -b /etc/DIR_COLORS)
    fi
fi
</code></pre>

<h1>Reset</h1>

<p>Color_Off=&ldquo;[\033[0m]&rdquo;       # Text Reset</p>

<h1>Regular Colors</h1>

<p>Black=&ldquo;[\033[0;30m]&rdquo;        # Black
Red=&ldquo;[\033[0;31m]&rdquo;          # Red
Green=&ldquo;[\033[0;32m]&rdquo;        # Green
Yellow=&ldquo;[\033[0;33m]&rdquo;       # Yellow
Blue=&ldquo;[\033[0;34m]&rdquo;         # Blue
Purple=&ldquo;[\033[0;35m]&rdquo;       # Purple
Cyan=&ldquo;[\033[0;36m]&rdquo;         # Cyan
White=&ldquo;[\033[0;37m]&rdquo;        # White</p>

<h1>Bold</h1>

<p>BBlack=&ldquo;[\033[1;30m]&rdquo;       # Black
BRed=&ldquo;[\033[1;31m]&rdquo;         # Red
BGreen=&ldquo;[\033[1;32m]&rdquo;       # Green
BYellow=&ldquo;[\033[1;33m]&rdquo;      # Yellow
BBlue=&ldquo;[\033[1;34m]&rdquo;        # Blue
BPurple=&ldquo;[\033[1;35m]&rdquo;      # Purple
BCyan=&ldquo;[\033[1;36m]&rdquo;        # Cyan
BWhite=&ldquo;[\033[1;37m]&rdquo;       # White</p>

<h1>Underline</h1>

<p>UBlack=&ldquo;[\033[4;30m]&rdquo;       # Black
URed=&ldquo;[\033[4;31m]&rdquo;         # Red
UGreen=&ldquo;[\033[4;32m]&rdquo;       # Green
UYellow=&ldquo;[\033[4;33m]&rdquo;      # Yellow
UBlue=&ldquo;[\033[4;34m]&rdquo;        # Blue
UPurple=&ldquo;[\033[4;35m]&rdquo;      # Purple
UCyan=&ldquo;[\033[4;36m]&rdquo;        # Cyan
UWhite=&ldquo;[\033[4;37m]&rdquo;       # White</p>

<h1>Background</h1>

<p>On_Black=&ldquo;[\033[40m]&rdquo;       # Black
On_Red=&ldquo;[\033[41m]&rdquo;         # Red
On_Green=&ldquo;[\033[42m]&rdquo;       # Green
On_Yellow=&ldquo;[\033[43m]&rdquo;      # Yellow
On_Blue=&ldquo;[\033[44m]&rdquo;        # Blue
On_Purple=&ldquo;[\033[45m]&rdquo;      # Purple
On_Cyan=&ldquo;[\033[46m]&rdquo;        # Cyan
On_White=&ldquo;[\033[47m]&rdquo;       # White</p>

<h1>High Intensty</h1>

<p>IBlack=&ldquo;[\033[0;90m]&rdquo;       # Black
IRed=&ldquo;[\033[0;91m]&rdquo;         # Red
IGreen=&ldquo;[\033[0;92m]&rdquo;       # Green
IYellow=&ldquo;[\033[0;93m]&rdquo;      # Yellow
IBlue=&ldquo;[\033[0;94m]&rdquo;        # Blue
IPurple=&ldquo;[\033[0;95m]&rdquo;      # Purple
ICyan=&ldquo;[\033[0;96m]&rdquo;        # Cyan
IWhite=&ldquo;[\033[0;97m]&rdquo;       # White</p>

<h1>Bold High Intensty</h1>

<p>BIBlack=&ldquo;[\033[1;90m]&rdquo;      # Black
BIRed=&ldquo;[\033[1;91m]&rdquo;        # Red
BIGreen=&ldquo;[\033[1;92m]&rdquo;      # Green
BIYellow=&ldquo;[\033[1;93m]&rdquo;     # Yellow
BIBlue=&ldquo;[\033[1;94m]&rdquo;       # Blue
BIPurple=&ldquo;[\033[1;95m]&rdquo;     # Purple
BICyan=&ldquo;[\033[1;96m]&rdquo;       # Cyan
BIWhite=&ldquo;[\033[1;97m]&rdquo;      # White</p>

<h1>High Intensty backgrounds</h1>

<p>On_IBlack=&ldquo;[\033[0;100m]&rdquo;   # Black
On_IRed=&ldquo;[\033[0;101m]&rdquo;     # Red
On_IGreen=&ldquo;[\033[0;102m]&rdquo;   # Green
On_IYellow=&ldquo;[\033[0;103m]&rdquo;  # Yellow
On_IBlue=&ldquo;[\033[0;104m]&rdquo;    # Blue
On_IPurple=&ldquo;[\033[10;95m]&rdquo;  # Purple
On_ICyan=&ldquo;[\033[0;106m]&rdquo;    # Cyan
On_IWhite=&ldquo;[\033[0;107m]&rdquo;   # White</p>

<h1>Random PS1 EDIT</h1>

<p>GIT_PS1_SHOWDIRTYSTATE=false</p>

<p>if [[ ${EUID} == 0 ]] ; then
  sq_color=$BRed
else
  sq_color=$BBlue
fi</p>

<p>export PS1=&ldquo;\n$sq_color\342\224\214\342\224\200\$([[ \$? != 0 ]] &amp;&amp; echo \&rdquo;[$BRed\342\234\227$sq_color]\342\224\200\&ldquo;)[$IBlack\t$sq_color]\342\224\200[[\033[01;37m]\u$sq_color]\342\224\200[$BGreen\w$sq_color]\n$sq_color\342\224\224\342\224\200\342\224\200> $BRed\$(&rdquo;&ldquo;) $sq_color\$ $Color_Off&rdquo;</p>

<pre><code>alias ls="ls --color=auto"
alias dir="dir --color=auto"
alias grep="grep --color=auto"
alias dmesg='dmesg --color'
man() {
    env LESS_TERMCAP_mb=$'\E[01;31m' \
    LESS_TERMCAP_md=$'\E[01;38;5;74m' \
    LESS_TERMCAP_me=$'\E[0m' \
    LESS_TERMCAP_se=$'\E[0m' \
    LESS_TERMCAP_so=$'\E[38;5;246m' \
    LESS_TERMCAP_ue=$'\E[0m' \
    LESS_TERMCAP_us=$'\E[04;38;5;146m' \
    man "$@"
}
</code></pre>

<p>else</p>

<pre><code># show root@ when we do not have colors

PS1="\u@\h \w \$([[ \$? != 0 ]] &amp;&amp; echo \":( \")\$ "

# Use this other PS1 string if you want \W for root and \w for all other users:
# PS1="\u@\h $(if [[ ${EUID} == 0 ]]; then echo '\W'; else echo '\w'; fi) \$([[ \$? != 0 ]] &amp;&amp; echo \":( \")\$ "
</code></pre>

<p>fi</p>

<p>PS2=&ldquo;> &rdquo;
PS3=&ldquo;> &rdquo;
PS4=&ldquo;+ &rdquo;</p>

<h1>Try to keep environment pollution down, EPA loves us.</h1>

<p>unset safe_term match_lhs</p>

<h1>Try to enable the auto-completion (type: &ldquo;pacman -S bash-completion&rdquo; to install it).</h1>

<p>[ -r /usr/share/bash-completion/bash_completion ] &amp;&amp; . /usr/share/bash-completion/bash_completion</p>

<h1>Try to enable the &ldquo;Command not found&rdquo; hook (&ldquo;pacman -S pkgfile&rdquo; to install it).</h1>

<h1>See also: <a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Bash#The_.22command_not_found.22_hook">https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Bash#The_.22command_not_found.22_hook</a></h1>

<p>[ -r /usr/share/doc/pkgfile/command-not-found.bash ] &amp;&amp; . /usr/share/doc/pkgfile/command-not-found.bash</p>

<p>archey
```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Youtube Making Us (Me) Lazy?]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/1393"/>
    <updated>2013-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/is-youtube-making-us-me-lazy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Long gone are the days when I spent nearly 8 hours reading a manual while making a stage 1 Gentoo install. Granted, most of those 8 hours were due to the compile times on the computer available to me at the time but a large part of it was spent reading huge walls of text on how to properly install, maintain, upgrade, tweak, work with emerge, etc..</p>

<p>If it were today, I think I’d Youtube it. I’m pretty sure there’s at least one video guide on how to do it. In fact, it’s not just <em>computer stuff</em> that I find myself searching on Youtube. I find myself choosing Youtube <em>instead</em> of googling for an alternative learning method who could possibly have more information than the video. If I then run into an issue that requires further investigation <em>only then</em> do I do a regular Google search for text.</p>

<p>I’m not quite sure what this means, or even if it means anything at all. Is that a sign that I’m getting lazy when it comes to do proper research? Do I need more information than what is present in a simple video? I suppose that will depend on who makes the video and what is chosen to be presented in it. But still..</p>

<p>There’s a world of information on Youtube. Ted is also quite decent, though it has a completely different scope. I’m unaware of any studies presenting conclusive data on whether people (like me) are starting to choose video as a preferred learning method. Someone better than me should probably do it, it sounds exciting.</p>

<p>What could this mean to the way things are traditionally taught across the globe? Will tablets with video content be used instead of books? Would I learn faster/better with video? There are plenty of possibilities and hypothesis about this, I’d like to know more about it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nexus 7]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/1323"/>
    <updated>2012-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/nexus-7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, yeah. I got a Nexus 7.</p>

<p>For a while now I&#8217;ve been tempted to get an e-paper Kindle so I could have the current book I&#8217;m reading with me at all times without having to carry the /sometimes/ equivalent of a cereal box with me. I kid you not, some of those Stephen King books are huge.</p>

<p>Though perfect for books, that&#8217;s all those Kindles are good for..books. There&#8217;s no other media consumption available for them. No video, no audio. Just books.</p>

<p>In the meantime, I found myself increasingly watching more and more youtube videos with tutorials/howtos and various other assorted stuff on my phone. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, my phone has the perfect size for a phone and I love it. But for videos that thing makes my eyes start to twitch after a while. That got me into the Kindle Fire territory. Books <em>and </em>media consumption.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>One thing led to another and if the Fire looked good with it&#8217;s size and price range, when the Nexus 7 came out I figured I might as well get a proper Android experience instead of an Amazon only thing. It&#8217;s true I could root and rom the Fire, but why go for all that trouble when I could just get the same thing directly from Google with the bonus effect that the Nexus is usually the first &#8220;brand&#8221; to get Android system updates? The screen on these tablets is far from being as comfortable to read as e-paper, but hey..I want my youtube videos. And truth be told, 1280*800 on a 7&#8243; screen makes for crisp clear text. My eyes have yet to complain even after spending a couple of hours straight staring at it. Typing on it is also a surprisingly good experience. My fat fingers that led me to get a phone with a physical qwerty keyboard are having no trouble at all finding those darned keys.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m glad the Nexus 7 was my first tablet, it&#8217;s a pretty good one as far as I can tell. I&#8217;m yet to find something to whine and moan about, and coming from me that&#8217;s a good thing. All in all, it&#8217;s the perfect price range with the perfect size in a little piece of really fast hardware with support directly from Google. If you&#8217;re considering getting one go for it.</p>

<p>I guess that a while not too long from now I&#8217;ll root and customize it to my liking as usual, but for now I&#8217;m enjoying the vanilla experience. Once a month has gone since when I got it is quite probably the ideal time to get into that sort of stuff. Until then, stay tuned for possible rooting guides as I&#8217;ll more than likely make a list of all the steps and procedures I take with the help of the fine folks at XDA and post it here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Take on What&#8217;s Wrong With Blackberry]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/1204"/>
    <updated>2012-04-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/my-take-on-whats-wrong-with-blackberry</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve recently begun looking for a new smartphone as my trusty <a href="http://www.gsmarena.com/samsung_i5700_galaxy_spica-2965.php" target="_blank">Spica</a> started to feel a bit..uh..old. Odd for a 1 year old phone to start feeling old but hey, it had already been out for quite some time before I got it. Menus and interaction was a bit sluggish at times, couldn&#8217;t install as many apps as I wanted because it&#8217;s available space was very limited, started missing some calls because it wouldn&#8217;t ring (no idea what caused it), had to constantly factory reset/reinstall rom because something would go bork and stop working, etc. While doing so, I remembered how much I loved the qwerty physical keyboard on my former phone, the <a href="http://www.gsmarena.com/nokia_e71-2425.php" target="_blank">Nokia E71</a>. With that in mind, I remembered how well regarded Blackberry phones are/used to be in that aspect, so I started checking out some online reviews.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Their <a href="http://www.gsmarena.com/blackberry_bold_touch_9900-3116.php" target="_blank">Bold</a> line of phones seems to be quite good and the physical keyboard is reported as probably the best out there and though Blackberry OS and app store doesn&#8217;t have nearly as many apps available as Android/iOS I think I could live with that since I&#8217;m not that much into games and most if not all essential apps I use on Android are available there as well. The issue with them is their price range, +500€ is simply put too much to shell out for what we get in return. Their keyboards may be great, but not <em>that</em> great. Especially when you consider that for that price you can get a phone with much better specs such as the <a href="http://www.gsmarena.com/samsung_i9100_galaxy_s_ii-3621.php" target="_blank">Samsung Galaxy S II</a>, <a href="http://www.gsmarena.com/samsung_galaxy_nexus-4219.php" target="_blank">Galaxy Nexus</a> or even the <a href="http://www.gsmarena.com/apple_iphone_4s-4212.php" target="_blank">iPhone 4S</a>. No qwerty physical keyboard, I&#8217;ll grant you that, but with screens big enough for that to be a non issue.</p>

<p>Into the Curve line of phones then. The <a href="http://www.gsmarena.com/blackberry_curve_9360-3722.php" target="_blank">9360</a> seems to be exactly the phone I&#8217;d buy. If it was at least 150€ cheaper, I mean. It&#8217;s seems to be a great phone. Qwerty keyboard (though not backlit like the Bold 9900), Blackberry OS 7, decent storage and app space, etc..but guys, it&#8217;s not a 300€ phone. Not even close.</p>

<p>This takes me to another issue I found with Blackberry recent handsets. Their batteries and battery life. A 1000mAh battery on a handset like the 9360? Really guys? I remember pulling almost a week&#8217;s worth of use out of the E71, though the Symbian version they used isn&#8217;t as battery intensive as most &#8220;modern&#8221; handset operating systems and hardware seem to be. I mean, people on the forums were complaining about 4 hours use before their phone went dead. That just doesn&#8217;t cut it. 300€ for a phone with it&#8217;s specs that lasts for less than half a day before it needs recharging? No thanks.</p>

<p>That said, I went and checked the other Curve phone available through my local cellphone operators, the <a href="http://www.gsmarena.com/blackberry_curve_8520-2889.php" target="_blank">8520</a>. 170€ for a phone with no 3G (Edge only), no GPS, Blackberry OS 5 as opposed to the current Blackberry OS 7, 256mb internal storage memory&#8230;are you even serious? I&#8217;d rather go for a cheap 50€ qwerty Huawei phone.</p>

<p>After further reading on what buyers had to say and online reviews I ended up going for the <a href="http://www.gsmarena.com/sony_ericsson_xperia_mini_pro-3713.php" target="_blank">Sony Ericsson Xperia Mini Pro</a>. A 1ghz Android handset, 512RAM/400mb storage, 5MP camera with HD video recording (although reviews suggested the camera isn&#8217;t that great and it really isn&#8217;t, I don&#8217;t really use my phones to take pictures), qwerty physical slide keyboard(!) which is pretty good/solidly built and changed what I used to think of slide keyboards, etc. Former Sony Ericsson model X10 Mini wasn&#8217;t impressive at all but this new line of &#8220;Mini&#8221; phones has been surprising a lot of people. All for&#8230;can you guess it? 170€. The same price I&#8217;d pay for a <em>really</em> outdated phone such as the Blackberry 8520. Hell, for 50€ more and I could even buy a <a href="http://www.gsmarena.com/samsung_google_nexus_s-3620.php" target="_blank">Nexus S</a>. A bit outdated but still a hell of an impressive phone.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll grant you the Mini Pro has a small(ish) 3&#8243; screen, but I don&#8217;t watch movies on phones, I don&#8217;t really read stuff in them for large amounts of time and when I do I find it surprising that I really don&#8217;t find such a small screen uncomfortable..that&#8217;s what made me look into Blackberries in the first place. Besides, a smaller screen drains the juice out of the battery far less than larger models and that is vital to me. But anyway, sheesh guys..if you put a premium price on something you better make sure it&#8217;s up to par with equivalent hardware. I don&#8217;t even mean Android phones that come up with a &#8220;best available specs phone&#8221; every couple of months or so..even the iPhone that has a somewhat inflated price for the hardware would be a better purchase than the Bold 9900 for the kind of money you&#8217;re asking.</p>

<p>Simply put, recheck your pricing model. The Bold 9900 isn&#8217;t a 500€ phone, more like 300€. The 9360 isn&#8217;t a 300€ phone, 150€. The 8520 would be a decent phone for 50€, though it&#8217;s *really* outdated.</p>

<p>The hardware is fine for what the phones are supposed to do, but their price is simply not justifiable when you glance at the next phone on the store shelf and see much better hardware for the same price range. One could say it&#8217;s the same as the Apple vs Android thing, but personal tastes aside your OS isn&#8217;t even comparable in the slightest to what Android/iOS has to offer for exactly the same price or sometimes for a hell of a lot less on Android&#8217;s case.</p>

<p>I really wanted to like Blackberries when I started hunting for a new phone to buy, I really did. But all I could think of was &#8220;are these guys serious?&#8221;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
