<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Games | ncatarino.github.io]]></title>
  <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/blog/categories/games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-22T18:39:26+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nuno Catarino]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barbarian or Monk? Monk or Barbarian?]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/1150"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/barbarian-or-monk-monk-or-barbarian</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I won this dumb online contest and I got a Diablo 3 beta key. I don&#8217;t usually win stuff but then again I don&#8217;t usually enter that many competitions either. Didn&#8217;t have to come up with something funny to say or anything, just insert name and email&#8230;then a few days later I got this email with &#8220;Congratulations you&#8217;re a winner, here&#8217;s a beta key.&#8221;. Good stuff.</p>

<p>Anyhoo, before I got into the beta I watched a crapton of playthrough videos on youtube and I kinda got into the Monk a lot though I also liked watching the Barbarian doing his stuff. For some reason I tend to favor melee characters on this kind of games. The exception is probably, oddly enough, Diablo 2..where I mostly played a Summoner Necromancer. You know, the guy who goes to the moor to grab a bazillion skeletons and then proceeds to faceroll whatever he wants to while watching a movie on the tv.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>After a few hours with each, got the Barbarian to 13 (max level at beta) and the Monk to 11. I have to say I enjoyed the Barbarian a <em>lot</em> more than the monk. And I also have to say I think the reason is because the gap closer charge thingie on the Barbarian is a <em>fury generator</em> and on the monk it&#8217;s a <em>spirit spender</em>. I know it may seem like not a big deal, but it just makes playing the Barbarian a lot more fun. I also seem to always be out of spirit with the Monk while with the Barbarian I found fury management to not be an issue. The Barbarian also feels like this massive dude who stomps his foot and breaks all tables in a 100 meter radius, that&#8217;s awesome.</p>

<p>So, yeah. Guess who will be playing a Barbarian May 15th. I already have the client preload file from battle.net, all there is to it now is waiting the <em>almost</em> two months till I can install it.</p>

<p>Played a bit with the Demon Hunter too but it felt a bit too much faceroll for me, I just pressed shift and shot at random till everything was dead. It&#8217;s a bit more fun to leap around and bash stuff with the Barbarian. I also noticed that as soon as something got near me and managed to land a hit my hp bar would take a dive <em>pretty darn fast</em>. Later in the game in Hell or Inferno I think they&#8217;ll have a lot of issues if there&#8217;s a boss in any way like Duriel in Diablo 3. That guy was a nightmare.</p>

<p>I plan to get all classes to 13 to get a feel for how they all play and spend some time looking at abilities and whatnot but I really think the main character I&#8217;ll be playing from release day onward is the big dude with a club that likes to bash things.</p>

<p>PS: Whoa, this new host is <em>faaaast.</em> I&#8217;m loving it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skyrim Crashing to Desktop]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/1120"/>
    <updated>2011-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/skyrim-crashing-to-desktop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, Skyrim is out. So many great games coming out that I think this winter will be spent with a blanket and me playing them. Battlefield 3 is a blast, takes a hell of a long time to unlock multiplayer stuff when compared to Bad Company 2 but I think it&#8217;s better this way. Modern Warfare 3 will have to wait since I don&#8217;t have the time nor wallet to get it right now.</p>

<p>I was having trouble and still do with Skyrim but I guess future patches will fix the odd bugs that always show up after initial launch. The first bug that I came upon was right after launch. I got the intro cinematics but as soon as a menu started to show up I was presented with my desktop and Skyrim would have simply crashed with no error message whatsoever. Making use of my Google Fu I found a fix, odd as it can be.</p>

<blockquote><p>Open Start Menu &#8211; Open Control Panel &#8211; Double click on Sound.</p>

<p>On the playback tab, right click on speakers or whatever has the green tick on your computer then click Properties.</p>

<p>Go to the Advanced tab and select 24 bit, 44100Hz (Studio Quality) in the menu.</p></blockquote>

<p>I&#8217;m still presented with random crashes every now and then, good thing I&#8217;m a savegame freak. I&#8217;m not quite sure what causes it but I suspect the nvidia drivers, I once caught one of the famous &#8220;driver XXX has crashed and successfully recovered&#8221; or whatever. No idea what causes this. Could be overheating but sensors say the videocard sits in the ~60ºC range, which is pretty darn acceptable if you ask me so I guess I&#8217;ll just keep on saving like a madman and hope for an eventual fix. It kinda screws game immersion for me :(</p>

<p><strong>EDIT:</strong> Had another annoying thing happen. There&#8217;s this part where we have to kill and loot an npc, what was happening was no loot was possible. I had the arrow on top of the dead npc pointing at his corpse but while hovering over him no &#8220;Press E to Search&#8221; was showing up. He was a tough bugger to kill, fortunately I could kill him with 3 arrow sneak attacks (focused on stealth and ranged). I saved and loaded a bunch of times, tried killing him melee&#8230;and nothing. Then I thought about loading a previous savegame. I noticed an &#8220;(Auto)&#8221; savegame from when I entered his chamber first and loaded that. Killed him and looted without a problem. Though annoying because he dropped a quest item this got me to thinking just how many other loot tables have I missed due to this? Feh. Still, hell of a game. Don&#8217;t miss it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[So, What&#8217;s New?]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/858"/>
    <updated>2011-07-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/so-whats-new</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">
  <a href="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/wtf.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-861" title="Slow Down!" src="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/wtf-300x196.jpg" alt="" width="180" height="118" /></a>So, after some time playing Rift and having some real life issues pull me away from any kind of gaming for the most part I found myself not really wanting to play it again. It&#8217;s a hell of a fine game, up till you reach max level. Though this is open for discussion, I found myself with nothing to do. Met some great people there and I&#8217;m keeping in touch with them for other gaming experiences but I&#8217;m done with Rift.
</p>


<p>That left a hole in my gaming schedule that I tried to fill with some stuff on Steam but I kept getting somewhat bored with everything there, then I thought of Eve Online.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Last time I played I left both characters logged inside a wormhole (I had to leave in a bit of a rush and hadn&#8217;t bothered resubbing up till now) and I assume that once I logged in I&#8217;d have no alternative but to self destruct both my boat and pod in order to get out of there since I had serious doubts my old corp/alliance would still be there. As it turns out, not only are they still there&#8230;I was in my home system when I logged. You know, the place where your medical clone is. In this case, high sec. I ended up loosing a few drakes and a few pvp boats but the Abaddon I was flying wasn&#8217;t lost. Woot!</p>

<p>Been playing it for a while now, not much has changed. Been considering moving into some sort of null space corp with the combat pilot since wormhole life burned me out a bit faster than I expected. All the scanning involved eventually got to me, I found myself spending more time scanning than actually doing something I enjoy. As for the other pilot, being so close to a Jump Freighter and Rorqual I figured I&#8217;d might as well take advantage of having jump skills already done and train him up for a carrier too. That should keep me busy for a while.</p>

<p>In the mean time I&#8217;ve been putting my excel fu to the test and doing some market work earning a few iskies in the process. Also, stuff is kind of unstable in Eve due to the micro transaction monoclegate but I won&#8217;t talk about it here.</p>

<p>But enough about games. I&#8217;m a huge nerd, that&#8217;s what you&#8217;re thinking. Right?</p>

<p>There&#8217;s on TV Show I&#8217;ve absolutely fell in love with. <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0944947/" target="_blank">Game of Thrones</a>. That thing is absolutely amazing, made me want to get the books and read them just so I know how the story develops and possibly ends. It has all the elements I love about stuff like the Dune universe like politics and schemes within schemes mixed with a fantasy world where dragons and undead are a threat. In one word, awesomeness.</p>

<p>Been watching <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1582457/" target="_blank">The Borgias</a> as well but I think I might have been spoiled by Game of Thrones since I find myself a bit bored while watching it and thinking about how good GoT is. If i&#8217;d seen this before GoT I&#8217;d have enjoyed it a <em>lot</em> more.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s it for now. Cheers :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Year Uptime, Rift and Some Other Stuff]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/843"/>
    <updated>2011-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/one-year-uptime-rift-and-some-other-stuff</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>No idea what was the exact day I bought the domain/hosting and started working on this site as a hobby, but it&#8217;s been roughly a year now. I know this because I had to renew it all, sometimes I wonder if it&#8217;s worth it since I end up spending quite some time without paying any attention to it. I guess that&#8217;s the nature of such sites :)</p>

<p>Been spending a *lot* of time playing Rift, I&#8217;m quite amazed how good something I&#8217;ve never heard of till about a couple of months ago can be. Couple of guys I know mentioned the open beta was up and I tried it. A few hours after I found myself buying it. I had recently restarted playing WoW but as soon as the month&#8217;s subscription ended I was finding myself really bored with it and Rift was entering it&#8217;s head start for pre-order customers. Perfect timing. Dragon Age 2 is supposed to be coming out too, that&#8217;s another one to check out.</p>

<p>Haven&#8217;t spent much time around my Spica as of lately, which is just as well since development for the Cyanogenmod Spica beta seems to have come to a halt. Probably because everything&#8217;s working quite well and it really shouldn&#8217;t be called a beta anymore. Been using the 8.3 beta for a few months now and it&#8217;s working like a charm.</p>

<p>Also, saw Tron Legacy the other day. Awesome sauce.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyanogen on the Spica, Gaming and a Small Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/823"/>
    <updated>2011-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/cyanogen-on-the-spica-gaming-and-a-small-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">
  <a href="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/spicaquadrant.png"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-826" title="spicaquadrant" src="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/spicaquadrant-200x300.png" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>So, it seems Cyanogenmod is here to stay on the Spica. Just as long as criminal (one of the developers @ samdroid.net) doesn&#8217;t feel like it&#8217;s time to call it quits. I&#8217;m now running alpha 8.2 and I can say everything pretty much just works. The camera is now in color and I&#8217;m yet to find something that doesn&#8217;t work like it&#8217;s intended. Supposedly hardware acceleration for divx doesn&#8217;t work, but I don&#8217;t watch divx on the phone anyway, so that&#8217;s fine.
</p>




<p style="text-align: justify;">
  There were also some 3D drivers released for the 8.1 ported from the Samsung Intercept ones, they boosted my phone&#8217;s score on Quadrant by a ton.  From the mid 400&#8242;s to the mid 600&#8242;s.  <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">Sadly they don&#8217;t work in 8.2 but I&#8217;m sure something is being done about it</span>. There has been an update to the drivers, still haven&#8217;t installed them but will do it pretty soon. Available <a href="http://forum.samdroid.net/f53/intercept-3d-drivers-cyanogemod-3601/#post95160" target="_blank">here</a>.
</p>




<p style="text-align: justify;">
  Haven&#8217;t posted here in a while, no special reason. My grandfather fell down and broke his hip, had to undergo surgery and eventually his age (87) and whatever comes with it caught up with him and he didn&#8217;t make it. He passed about a week after surgery. And that was pretty effed up.
</p>




<p style="text-align: justify;">
  <!--more-->
</p>




<p style="text-align: justify;">
  After that I took some time off of everything, my grandmother has alzheimer&#8217;s and can&#8217;t quite be left alone so she&#8217;s staying here at my place for the time being. All this time at home made me start serious gaming routines to pass the time. Been having tons of fun with Blood Bowl Legendary Edition and a few other games I got on Steam&#8217;s christmas deals. Blood Bowl really is a ton of fun once you get the grasp of the rules and how it&#8217;s played, have a few friends who already played it and kept on and on talking about it and when I saw it on sale at Steam I just couldn&#8217;t resist it. The only other game that has been able to keep me away from Blood Bowl is Dead Rising 2. I played the Demo on the 360 and didn&#8217;t really like it but then I gave it a little shot on the PC and it somehow feels different. It can be hella fun. What&#8217;s there not to love in zombies and a gazillion and one possible weapons to smash their heads?
</p>




<p style="text-align: center;">
  httpv://youtube.com/watch?v=x-0iMaPLgQc
</p>




<p style="text-align: center;">
  httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uUdA2VVNY3w
</p>




<p style="text-align: left;">
  Spent both christmas and new year&#8217;s with the family, couldn&#8217;t quite get myself to go out and party. Really didn&#8217;t felt like it. So&#8230;this thing needed and update and I guess this is it :)
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
