<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: TV | ncatarino.github.io]]></title>
  <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/blog/categories/tv/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-22T18:37:32+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nuno Catarino]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Torchwood]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/1012"/>
    <updated>2011-08-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/torchwood</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">
  <a href="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/torchwood-banner.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1013" title="torchwood-banner" src="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/torchwood-banner.jpg" alt="" width="576" height="202" /></a>
</p>




<p style="text-align: left;">
  This show is really good, I&#8217;m surprised. I checked some Dr. Who a while ago and didn&#8217;t find it much to my taste but decided to give Torchwood a go, maybe I should check Dr. Who again.
</p>




<p style="text-align: left;">
  <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0485301/" target="_blank">Imdb</a></span>
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Falling Skies]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/921"/>
    <updated>2011-07-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/falling-skies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/falling_skies_logo.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-922" title="falling_skies_logo" src="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/falling_skies_logo-1024x528.jpg" alt="" width="620" height="319" /></a></p>

<p>Spielberg. The aftermath of an alien invasion. Dude what was in ER. Works for me.</p>

<p>A friend told me about this after I whined about how great Game of Thrones was and now I had nothing to watch. Turns out it&#8217;s not bad, not bad at all. I&#8217;d like to see more alien tech instead of all the drama going on but I guess they don&#8217;t want to shoot all their shells before they know what kind of ground they&#8217;re stepping on.</p>

<p>More info at <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1462059/" target="_blank">IMDB</a></span>.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[So, What&#8217;s New?]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/858"/>
    <updated>2011-07-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/so-whats-new</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">
  <a href="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/wtf.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-861" title="Slow Down!" src="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/wtf-300x196.jpg" alt="" width="180" height="118" /></a>So, after some time playing Rift and having some real life issues pull me away from any kind of gaming for the most part I found myself not really wanting to play it again. It&#8217;s a hell of a fine game, up till you reach max level. Though this is open for discussion, I found myself with nothing to do. Met some great people there and I&#8217;m keeping in touch with them for other gaming experiences but I&#8217;m done with Rift.
</p>


<p>That left a hole in my gaming schedule that I tried to fill with some stuff on Steam but I kept getting somewhat bored with everything there, then I thought of Eve Online.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Last time I played I left both characters logged inside a wormhole (I had to leave in a bit of a rush and hadn&#8217;t bothered resubbing up till now) and I assume that once I logged in I&#8217;d have no alternative but to self destruct both my boat and pod in order to get out of there since I had serious doubts my old corp/alliance would still be there. As it turns out, not only are they still there&#8230;I was in my home system when I logged. You know, the place where your medical clone is. In this case, high sec. I ended up loosing a few drakes and a few pvp boats but the Abaddon I was flying wasn&#8217;t lost. Woot!</p>

<p>Been playing it for a while now, not much has changed. Been considering moving into some sort of null space corp with the combat pilot since wormhole life burned me out a bit faster than I expected. All the scanning involved eventually got to me, I found myself spending more time scanning than actually doing something I enjoy. As for the other pilot, being so close to a Jump Freighter and Rorqual I figured I&#8217;d might as well take advantage of having jump skills already done and train him up for a carrier too. That should keep me busy for a while.</p>

<p>In the mean time I&#8217;ve been putting my excel fu to the test and doing some market work earning a few iskies in the process. Also, stuff is kind of unstable in Eve due to the micro transaction monoclegate but I won&#8217;t talk about it here.</p>

<p>But enough about games. I&#8217;m a huge nerd, that&#8217;s what you&#8217;re thinking. Right?</p>

<p>There&#8217;s on TV Show I&#8217;ve absolutely fell in love with. <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0944947/" target="_blank">Game of Thrones</a>. That thing is absolutely amazing, made me want to get the books and read them just so I know how the story develops and possibly ends. It has all the elements I love about stuff like the Dune universe like politics and schemes within schemes mixed with a fantasy world where dragons and undead are a threat. In one word, awesomeness.</p>

<p>Been watching <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1582457/" target="_blank">The Borgias</a> as well but I think I might have been spoiled by Game of Thrones since I find myself a bit bored while watching it and thinking about how good GoT is. If i&#8217;d seen this before GoT I&#8217;d have enjoyed it a <em>lot</em> more.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s it for now. Cheers :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Lost Should Have Ended. No, Seriously.]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/492"/>
    <updated>2010-05-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/how-lost-should-have-ended-no-seriously</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>[<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-493" title="2OXLq" src="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/2OXLq.gif" alt="" width="237" height="125" />][1]</p>

<p style="text-align: center;">
  Was it just me that hated the ending they gave to Lost?
</p>




<p><p style="text-align: center;">
  <p style="text-align: center;"></p>

<pre><code>via &lt;a href="http://www.geeksaresexy.net/2010/05/26/how-lost-should-have-ended-animated-gif/" target="_blank"&gt;geeksaresexy&lt;/a&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>  </p></p>

<p> [1]: <a href="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/2OXLq.gif">http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/2OXLq.gif</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
