<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Photography | ncatarino.github.io]]></title>
  <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/blog/categories/photography/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-22T15:33:10+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nuno Catarino]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Art of Glitching]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/1262"/>
    <updated>2012-05-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/the-art-of-glitching</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">
  So, a friend of mine asked me for any piece of mac or windows software that would &#8220;glitch&#8221; images as he needs it for some artsy thing. I didn&#8217;t quite understand what he was after at first, but when the conversation continued and I put my Google Fu to work I realized people were glitching images as an art form. You know when sometimes there&#8217;s data corruption on your hard or usb drive? Images get all twisted and/or with a crapton of artifacts in it. Glitching is the art of doing it on purpose! It&#8217;s also hella fun to look at the result in some cases. Here&#8217;s a &#8216;glitched&#8217; image so you can have a better perception of what I&#8217;m talking about. Non glitched on the left, glitched on the right. Click them to see a bigger picture.
</p>




<p style="text-align: center;">
  <a href="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/nonwarp.png"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-1263" title="Non Glitched" src="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/nonwarp-112x150.png" alt="Non Glitched" width="112" height="150" /></a> <a href="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/warped.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-1264" title="Glitched" src="http://ncatarino.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/warped-112x150.jpg" alt="Glitched" width="112" height="150" /></a>
</p>




<p style="text-align: left;">
  Looks great, doesn&#8217;t it? But how exactly does one do this? Well&#8230;read on, friend.
</p>




<!--more-->




<p style="text-align: left;">
  At first I started looking for a Photoshop plugin because if it exists, there&#8217;s a Photoshop plugin for it. Right? Wrong. The only plugin I found related in any way to this was an After Effects plugin, and that&#8217;s video. Apparently glitching is also used in video, they call it datamoshing. Cool name.
</p>




<p style="text-align: left;">
  Following that and as I entered Zen State in my Google Fu, I discovered enlightenment. You only need Paint and Wordpad to do this. Two common Windows pieces of software no one would ever consider when doing <em>serious business</em> image editing. You open the image in Paint and save it in .bmp (bitmap) format as this format renders the file less &#8216;fragile&#8217; to the procedure that follows. And yes, it&#8217;s important you use Paint for some reason. I tried saving it on Irfanview and it didn&#8217;t work. Next up you open Wordpad and drop the file in it, just click the file and drag it into Wordpad. Press &#8216;Save&#8217; once and that&#8217;s it. Congrats, you glitched an image. For some god knows why reason (ehh, I&#8217;m sure some nerd can explain it) the file generated is a corrupt version of the previous image.
</p>




<p style="text-align: left;">
  So, yeah. I guess the next step is to google for ALL the images (if you know what I mean) and glitch them? Fun, fun, fun!
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inauguração &#8211; Estúdio Mahtab Danças Étnicas]]></title>
    <link href="http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/272"/>
    <updated>2010-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ncatarino.github.io/archives/inauguracao-estudio-mahtab-dancas-etnicas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">
  No próximo fim de semana de 27/28 Março de 2010 vai ser inaugurado o Estúdio Mahtab Danças Étnicas.
</p>




<p style="text-align: left;">
  Mesmo a calhar, assim dá para brincar com a nova objectiva para a máquina. Se o sítio não tiver muita luz espero é que não se importem com o flash, não me tou bem a ver levar o tripé. Provavelmente a maioria das oportunidades de disparo serão de coisas em movimento, acaba por ser meio irrelevante ter ou não tripé.
</p>




<p style="text-align: left;">
  É porreiro ver malta amiga e conhecida conseguir pouco a pouco o que quer :) Fico contente que este pessoal tenha conseguido o espaço e leve adiante a ideia de tornar a dança ainda mais parte da sua vida.
</p>




<p style="text-align: left;">
  Flyer e mais informação <a href="http://www.myspace.com/mahtabbellydance" target="_blank">aqui</a>.
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
